You two-faced devil.
You played a game again!
The game is over, Bala.
I will be the death of all of you.
You can't do anything to us, Sofia.
Burn the carts!
Alps, protect the cart!
Alps! Put out the fire on the cart, come on!
Gonca! Fatma, Halime!
Protect the Alps!
As you order, mother!
Claudius knew we were coming.
And he also knew the road we were taking.
But how could he know this, my Bey?
Now that dog will build a
defense line at Mudurnu Castle.
What will we do, Osman Bey?
We fell into an ambush and had to turn back.
You know the condition of our men.
There are wounded ones.
We will set up a quarters in Goynuk.
Let things calm down first.
Then we will make our move.
But we will never give up on war or conquests.
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
This is the loot we shared for Goynuk, my Bey.
Lands are taken with swords.
A land is conquered by the sword...
...but it can only be ruled with
justice, its nation and consent.
Now this gold will improve Goynuk.
The non-Muslims will lack nothing.
I don't want to see anyone in poverty.
For this reason, Koca Bey, this duty is yours.
You will be the commander
here. Now go and fulfill your duty.
As my Osman Bey orders.
Goynuk will be rebuilt with the justice of Islam.
God willing. God willing.
Boran, Turhan. -My Bey.
You..
You will go to Mudurnu Castle.
You will get inside secretly.
You'll learn how many soldiers are there
the situation of the walls, everything.
-As you order, my Bey.
Come on, brother.
Turgut Ghazi, come.
Let's talk.
Let's talk, Osman. Let's talk.
Sofia.
You are wounded. We must retreat.
Get out of my way.
Bala! I will kill you with
your daughter's dagger.
Halime.
Sister!
Sofia.
Poena..
Soldiers, we are retreating.
My daughter...
My daughter, what did you do?
Halime.
Halime, what did you do?!
My daughter!
They are running away. Alps, follow them!
I will take your life with my own hands, Sofia.
My Halime.
Halime, hold on, hold on
my daughter, you'll be alright.
You will be alright, my daughter.
No, no, my daughter, you will be alright.
Hold on, my daughter, you will be alright.
Alps, put the goods down.
We will take Halime to Goynuk now. Come on!
Hold on, my daughter, you will be alright.
How is this possible?
We expected you with a greater army, Claudius.
Is that so, Nikitas?
I sacrificed my men.
To push Osman back.
To protect Mudurnu. Do you understand?
Osman's target is here.
Today I pushed him back. But
he will come again tomorrow.
It is very hard to defend Mudurnu in this state.
You will defend it.
Women, children, the
elderly, everyone will fight!
We will not give Mudurnu to him.
I have a spy inside who informs
me of Osman's every step.
We will learn his plans and take precautions.
It was impossible for Claudius to know
which road we would take to Mudurnu.
If the enemy knows where to hit, it means
he has become friends with our friend.
Clearly, there is a traitor among us, Osman.
We have built a state in
the nests of many enemies.
We have defeated many of them.
But these traitors among us...
They always block our way.
It was like this before,
it will always be like this.
The Oghuzs' sleep is deep,
and its traitor is sneaky.
But a Bey never sleeps.
He always lives with suspicion.
This is your burden, Osman.
Sure it is. Of course.
A wolf never forgets the
plain where he was ambushed.
I will find that snake, one way or another.
But our target will not change.
We will make Mudurnu the land
of the Turks, one way or another.
Sure we will.
However, the walls of Mudurnu
Castle are high and strong.
Our Alps are tired.
The Turkmens who set out
from Aleppo still have not arrived.
It is clear that their
arrival will take a long time.
We must make a move so that
we do not face defeat, my Osman.
We will. We will.
Our Allah Who opens the way of battles
for us will surely enlighten our path.
Surely.
We will be victorious.
We will be victorious. There is no other way.
We will be, with Allah's help. We will.
We will be victorious.
Halime.
What have you done, dear?
What have you done? Hold on.
She's bleeding too much. Hold on, dear.
You will be alright.
-It's alright.
-Hold on, sister.
-Mother.
-Yes, my dear? Yes, Halime?
Go on. You're good.
-Mother.
-Yes, my dear?
Pardon me in this world and afterworld.
No. Don't say such things. You're good.
It's alright. Halime? Halime, open your eyes.
Open your eyes.
Cerkutay!
Cerkutay, you go ahead and
let Alaaddin know! Come on!
The damage in Goynuk will be assessed.
The destroyed marketplace will be built again.
It's easy to build a new one. But we
need to restore the merchants' trust.
Their loss will be covered
and they will be helped.
Goynuk will be the trade center
of the provinces around again.
Justice is important in trade.
Both the merchants and the state should earn.
We should establish communities for that, huh?
We will.
Yigit, gather the prominent
merchants of Greek people.
My odalisque... Eleni Hatun.
She will be very useful for
winning the hearts of Greek people.
I have no doubts.
Yet you should be careful, Yigit.
Remember. A single Chinese princess
was enough to destroy their homeland.
Indeed.
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too.
Osman Bey is waiting.
-Let's not keep Osman Bey waiting.
-We shouldn't.
A riot fire will start in Goynuk.
Sofia will make the fire grow bigger.
A Turk never hits without fighting.
We will start shooting the
walls of Mudurnu tomorrow.
-God willing, my Bey.
Alaaddin, tell me. Are the
battering rams and catapults ready?
Catapults are ready, my Bey.
The rams have been reinforced.
We're standing ready for the raid with your call.
Thank you.
Koca Bey, tell me.
What is the situation?
The booties of Goynuk improved our situation.
Yet alps are exhausted, my Bey.
I'm just worried...
I don't know what we could do if
alps can't fight during the raid tomorrow.
My brother is right.
Besides, they say the walls of
Mudurnu are too strong, Osman Bey.
Do you think we can pass?
Osman Bey, I agree with the Beys.
If we get defeated in front of the
walls, it may be devastating for us.
I understand your concerns.
As I turned Goynuk into a land of Turks,
...I have a good move about Mudurnu.
One way or another, we will make
a huge hole in the walls of Mudurnu.
God willing, my Bey.
-God willing.
-God willing, my Bey.
With all the alps and soldiers we have,
we will be ready in the morning prayer.
While the noon sun is at the top,
...the azan-i Muhammadi will
be recited in Mudurnu, God willing.
-God willing.
May I come, my Bey?
Come in, Samil.
May your conquest be blessed, my Bey.
Thank you.
What's the situation of nomads?
I informed all of them about your move, my Bey.
Warriors whose swords rusting in the sheathes...
...have turned their faces to
the frontiers, the lands of Kayi.
Alright, alright.
With them, we will make these
lands a permanent homeland for us.
God willing, my Bey.
When I told them about your cause
in Susa, they welcomed the news.
All of them will follow you to serve Islam.
Alright, alright.
Well..
We will fight for Islam to
the last drop of our blood.
God willing, my Bey.
-God willing.
-God willing, my Bey.
Do I have permission, my Bey?
Aykurt, come in.
My Bey, Bala Hatun is coming.
They say the situation isn't good.
-What?
-What are you talking about?
My Bey!
My Shahzade!
Alaaddin Bey! My Shahzade!
Help!
My Shahzade!
Alaaddin Bey!
What's the matter Cerkutay?
What is the problem?
My Bey.
Some got wounded.
-Hold on, sister. Brother!
-Alaaddin!
-Brother!
Gonca?
Alaaddin, help!
-Hold on, Halime. It's alright.
-Bala!
Help, son
-What's going on, Gonca?
-Alaaddin, help!
-Brother, help!
-Mother, what happened?
-Sister.
-Bleeding too much. We couldn't stop it.
-Hold her. Easy.
-Hold on.
Bring a stretcher!
-Bring a stretcher now! -A stretcher!
-Come on!
-Who did this?
Bring it. Let me.
-Easy, easy.
-Carry her! Come on!
-Come on.
-You will be alright, sister.
-Our child is dying, Osman.
She risked her life for me. I couldn't stop her.
-Who did this?
-Sofia. She ambushed the caravan.
Snake has changed her skin, huh?
Seyit, come closer.
What is it?
Give this to Claudius immediately.
He should be cautious.
Osman is going to besiege the
castle of Mudurnu tomorrow morning.
He has a plan.
I couldn't figure it out but strict
measures can stop his plan.
Go now.
What's going on, Yigit Bey?
Where are you sending Seyit Alp?
To my tribe.
My merchants and goods will
come to the marketplace of Goynuk.
It seems you are the one who will benefit
from the market thing most, Yigit Bey.
Yes.
Well... Fertility lies in trade.
There the market is! You
can trade too, Hasan Bey.
No.
I trade with weapons and find gold in the booty.
The market shall be yours and
the battlefield mine, Yigit Bey.
Right.
Right
Peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you too, my Bey.
-Peace be upon you too.
What's the matter, alps?
Pull yourselves together.
Heathens repelled us. We
got defeated, Turgut Ghazi.
Our swords are ashamed of
getting out of their sheathes.
What are you saying? Why would you say that?
Don't you remember the night smelling like rain?
Have you forgotten the story of
Kurshad and his forty warriors?
To stop the cruelty of China,
...they passed so-called impassable walls.
They went to the palace which was
protected by thousands of guards,
...fought a battle which a mind can't
comprehend and courage wasn't enough for.
...and they stuck the sword of
justice into the dark flag of China!
Forty warriors and forty believer
hearts fought for their freedom.
They broke the heart of
the cruel emperor with fea
...and made him run away from the palace.
Now tell me, alps.
Don't you have the power
in your veins that took
Kurshad and his forty
fighters to the Chinese palace?
We do, Turgut Ghazi!
You say you do, huh?
Then be worthy of your ancestors.
Courage is for us and cowardice for the enemy!
Martyrdom is for us and death for the heathens!
We shall move forward!
And only Allah knows if we come back or not.
Okay.
Allah tested even our Prophet Hadhrat Muhammad
Mustafa with a defeat.
You can't be victorious all the time, alps.
If you don't suffer, you
can't even call it a victory.
Remember. The heart of a
volunteer is the greatest heart.
We are soldiers whose hearts
are full with desire of fighting.
We raise our swords for only Almighty Allah...
...and lower them for justice.
We will either win the war
or become martyrs for liberty.
Allah is the greatest! Allah is the greatest!
First, we need to strengthen the walls.
Your men are really stupid.
Soldiers!
Repair the walls!
Strengthen them! Now!
Finally.
Brother, we have to be cautious.
Okay.
By the order of the Great Emperor...
...we are rekindling the great Byzantine fire.
You will all protect this castle like knights.
We will make Osman experience
a defeat he will never forget.
Everything is for the Great Rome!
For the Great Rome! For the Great Rome!
Get the people to their places.
Everyone will learn how to fight.
Quickly.
Come on!
Sofia.
The snake has returned to its nest.
Brother, first we will get out of this crowd.
Then we will wear these
dogs' soldier clothes. Come on.
Okay Boran Bey.
Sofia, you are not saying anything.
You are wounded.
Are you alright?
It seems Osman defeated you.
Tell me you stopped the help going to the tribe.
If that help reaches Osman, they
will be at the walls before night.
I burned it all. They will not receive help.
Then what happened to you?
Why do you look like you have lost?
Have you started to feel mercy for them?
Never.
For victory, I killed Poena,
whom I raised with my own hands.
I killed mercy, I killed love.
For victory.
I will no longer pity anyone.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
It happened because of me.
I could not protect her. I should
have been injured, not her.
Bala, how can you say that?
It has nothing to do with you.
It all happened because of Sofia.
That snake will pay for what she did.
She is testing us again with the same pain.
I should never have trusted her.
The evil alliance united again.
Two-faced devil.
The Emperor took Claudius
and Sofia with him again.
Whoever hurts our children...
They will surely pay the price for this. Surely.
My daughter.
She is waking up.
Halime.
Father.
Alaeddin, tell us something good, my son.
I will save my sister, mother.
I will treat her. Don't worry.
Fools!
Get up! Get up!
You damned woman!
Children who can hold weapons
will fight with the soldiers.
Women and the elderly will carry ammunition.
These fools who cannot work and only
cry will be at the front in the battle.
Let them be useful before they die.
Brother.
I have never seen people that treat
their own people with such cruelty.
Soon these dogs will die.
Let's find a weakness first.
Let's find one, come on. Let's find it.
Brother.
Look, look. Look.
Come on. Come on.
Koca Bey, has order been restored in Goynuk?
What is the situation of the Greek people?
We have rebuilt the places that
were burned and destroyed, my Bey.
We talked to the merchants, listened
to their problems, and met their needs.
Good.
The people have suffered so much oppression
that they long for justice, my Bey.
First Goynuk, then Mudurnu...
Then the lands held by the infidels.
All will be freed from oppression, God willing.
We will set out tomorrow..
With Allah's permission, my Bey.
Bala.
Bala, the main duty is yours.
Goynuk is entrusted to you.
As you order, my Bey.
Justice will rule in Goynuk. The
voice of the oppressed will be heard.
Okay, okay.
Take care of the prisoners and female slaves.
The girls who want to get
married will marry our Alps.
We will bring such an order to this land that...
We will establish a foundation to
help young Alps and sisters get married.
This way every home
will be a pillar of the state.
You have thought well, my Bey.
The continuation of the generation
is the survival of the state..
I will take care of this quickly, my Bey.
Starting a family and raising
generations is as important as fighting.
If you allow me, the sisters and I
will carry this burden together, huh?
I am not allowing you. I am entrusting it to you.
The heart of the state beats in
the battlefield and in the houses.
Therefore, the foundation we
will establish will be our symbol.
God willing my Bey.
God willing.
Osman has turned Goynuk into a headquarters.
Tomorrow, he will set out
from there and attack Mudurnu.
Let him come.
My soldiers are more angry than
ever. We will never give Mudurnu to him.
While you destroy Osman here, I will...
...set a big fire in Goynuk.
Placing Eleni near Yigit was smart.
She is about to complete the preparations.
She will also inform Yigit about the rebellion.
This is the farthest point of the city.
They throw the garbage here.
Only we know this secret entrance.
Tomorrow Eleni will let you in through there.
It doesn't matter, Claudius.
Tomorrow I will light such a big
fire of rebellion in Goynuk that...
...Bala will burn to ashes.
We will set a hellish trap for
Osman here that he will never forget.
Tomorrow those dirty Turks
will be destroyed forever.
For the great Byzantium.
What are these, Hatun?
Flying flames.
Who are you?
I did not choose you just
because you are brave Yigit Bey.
You chose me?
I was placed beside you by Claudius' order.
Claudius.
Look, everything is ready.
Tomorrow a rebellion will start
in Goynuk to destroy the Turks.
The siege of Mudurnu...
...will cause Osman to lose Goynuk.
Spare my child's life, my Allah.
You're the One Who gives and takes lives.
How is she doing? Better?
She's not waking up, Osman.
Her breath is too weak.
What will I do if she doesn't
open her beautiful eyes again?
I went through this once.
Don't make me go there again, my Allah.
Hush, Bala.
My daughter.
Halime.
Thinking takes away my breath.
I'm so scared.
Hush. Don't do this.
She got over many things
and will get over this too.
Don't worry.
She's a stubborn one just like you.
She takes strength from you too.
You are here for her.
So she will wake up.
She used to do the same before.
She used to keep saying your
name when she got a fever.
-You go have some rest.
-No, my Bey.
You're going to have a battle
in Mudurnu in the morning.
I will wait here. You go rest.
You will need to take care of
Goynuk and our children, anyway.
You go have some rest.
I will rest later.
Don't worry. She will be alright.
Come on, Bala. Come on.
-Fine.
How will we get out?
We'll go north, brother.
The woods will restrain their sight.
We need to be quick, Turahan.
Osman Bey is expecting intelligence.
Okay.
Take this.
Come on, man.
Someone's coming.
You go first.
It's my turn.
Be quick, brother.
In the name of Allah.
What's going on here?
I'm talking to you.
Now it's good. They got what they deserved.
Allah Almighty speaks the truth.
The Most Merciful of the merciful.
My Allah, The Greatest of the great.
You are the One Who heals
everyone with Your name "Healer".
O Creator, heal my Halime.
Don't let our joy be spoiled, my Allah.
Even with grief, mourning
and sorrow in our hearts,
...we will fight to spread Your
name around the whole world.
My Allah, give me and my army strength.
Give me a chance to ruin the games of the enemy.
You let me conquer Goynuk.
My Allah, please let me conquer Mudurnu too.
Make us victorious, my Allah.
Aameen, my Allah.
Aameen. Aameen, O Creator.
Aameen
Everybody grab their weapons.
You did everything I said, right, Eleni?
I unlocked the door of the prisoners.
People are gathering in the square.
They all have a grudge with Osman.
Good.
Women and children will walk in the front.
Our soldiers among people
will set fire to everything.
Now go and hide somewhere.
Sofia.
We're throwing our innocent people into the fire.
They should be burned in the
fire so Rome will stand, Hristo.
Don't you still get it?
Children... How about they stay out of this?
Move, Hristo. Move.
Take the rest to the storehouses. Come on.
May your work be easy.
Allah Allah?!
Did I hear right?
You aren't saying bad
words to me for the first time.
Fine. I won't speak then.
Please just talk to me.
What did you say?
Your sister, I said... Is she alright?
We are waiting.
She hasn't opened her eyes yet.
If she's strong like you, she will open her eyes.
She'll wake up.
I came here to thank you.
You risked your life for us.
Thank you.
My Allah..
So many good words for me is
too much for me in one day, Kayi...
Fatma Hatun, is this the end of the world?
I don't know if it's the end of the world
...but too many good words
drive you crazy, I guess.
Yes, that's it!
She calls me crazy again!
Oghuz Bey!
Fatma Hatun! People are rioting!
There is a chaos in the square!
What are you saying?
-If we don't repress the riot, Goynuk will fall.
-That won't happen!
Some alps will stay in the
castle. We are going to the square.
I will let my mother know.
Sisters will be with you.
Be careful, Fatma Hatun.
Come on, alps!
Come onz alps!
Turks! Turks are coming!
Turks are coming!
-Everybody line up!
-Come on!
-Hurry up! They are coming!
-Come on, come on!
-Gather up!
-Hurry up!
-They are coming!
Osman is here with all his strength.
There is nobody in Goynuk.
Good.
Come closer, Osman.
Come.
I will give you a defeat
that you can never forget.
My walls will swallow your catapult shots.
You will go mad. Come
O Mudurnu!
The history of Turks will be
made here today, God willing.
My Bey.
What's the situation?
The castle is full of soldiers.
The walls are strong rocks. But there
is a water channel in the west, my Bey.
It's the weakest spot, my Bey.
Listen to me carefully.
She looks better than yesterday, huh?
She will be better.
She will be.
Right, my honey?
My Halime.
My dear.
Open your eyes.
Your mother is here.
-Mother! Mother.
-Yes, dear?
Prisoners have escaped.
People gathered and started a riot.
There is a huge chaos.
What are you saying?
No. We can't let hem do that.
You stay with your sister, dear.
-Gonca, let's go. Come on, dear.
-Let's go.
We understood everything, my Bey.
Even if it costs us our lives, we will
fulfill this duty with Allah's permission.
Thank you.
Go safely. Go now. Come on.
-As you order, my Bey.
-Okay my Bey.
Alkeyta, Dogan, you come with us.
Alaeddin.
My Bey.
Turn the catapults to the north immediately.
Boran and Turhan will go on duty now.
As my Bey orders.
The elderly of my tribe!
My Beys!
My brave men!
Now the infidels are waiting
for us behind the walls!
Today, this is the battlefield where The Righteous
and the falsehood will stand against each other.
Tell me. Will you fight with me here?!
-We will, Osman Bey!
Are you ready to drink the sherbet of shahada
(metaphor for swear to die in the name of Allah)?
We are, Osman Bey!
Allah is the Greatest!
You hear the voices of Turks, right?
They are trying to scare us!
But they do not know that nothing and...
...no one can scare the soldiers of Rome!
Now, in Goynuk, the rebellion fire
of Rome is burning the place down!
And we will fight with our honour here!
In the end..
...we will be victorious!
We will be victorious!
Ya Allah..
Allah is the Greatest!
Stand tall, strong soldiers of Rome!
Turks' cannons cannot do anything to us!
Keep firing, Osman!
You can only raise the dust of
these walls with those cannons!
Fire!
Is this all you can do, Osman?
My Bey.
The catapults won't be able
to break the walls of the castle.
Even if we strike the walls for months, it's
impossible, we won't be able to get through.
Don't worry.
We will make a move for sure.
Give us the good news, my Bey.
What is your plan?
Soon it will be revealed.
Be quiet brothers. Come on.
Hope will spread everywhere, brothers.
Hope for Kayis, death for the enemy.
In the name of Allah,
O Allah, brother!
Come on! Come on!
Turks! -The wall of shields!
Is this all you can do?
Do you think you can break
through these walls like this?
You foolish shepherd!
Fire! Fire!
What is happening there?
What is happening there?!
They opened a breach there, Claudius.
Thanks to Allah.
We opened a breach in Mudurnu's walls!
Alps!
Attack!
You are as strong as your name, Dogan!
Your words make me proud, Koca Bey!
Allah is the Greatest!
Give me the flag!
To the breach!
All soldiers, go to the breaches and defend!
Claudius!
We will either die or take our city back!
The children of Byzantine Empire.
You are all soldiers of our Emperor!
The dastards who killed your lord
will not show mercy to you either.
And you know this. Their
cruelty has already begun.
And we will not allow this.
We will either die or take back our city.
You stay here.
When things get chaotic here,
you will let us into the castle.
Alps, keep your shields with you.
Bala.
So you are here.
Bala Hatun, what will we do?
They placed the children in front
of them and armed themselves.
No, this is not something
they can do on their own.
Oguz.
Bahadir, take precautions, let
the archers take their positions.
They won't make a move until we say so.
-As you order Bala Hatun.
O people, we will not harm you.
To avoid harm to anyone go home immediately.
Immediately!
This is a game. That archer is not one of us.
Oguz, go after him!
People!
We are not shooting the arrow!
You are falling for their game.
We will not harm you.
This is my last warning.
Go home, now!
Alps!
Shields! Forward!
Protect the children, sisters.
I will not hand over my castle to you, Osman!
This land belongs to Rome!
Wherever my horse's hooves step is mine.
We will send you away from this land like dogs.
Byzantine dogs.
Allah is the Greatest!
The castle has fallen, sir.
We are retreating. To the gates!
Take down that flag.
Allah is the Greatest!
Glory is yours, honor is yours.
Fly freely, my flag!
Allah is the Greatest!
You are making a mistake.
You will lose your lives for nothing.
Stop, retreat!
Surrender and go home, people.
We are not your enemy, what are you doing?
Stop!
We will not harm you.
You took everything from me.
I will take everything from you.
Hristo.
Let s start.
Bala!
You snake!
It was you of course!
You used them as your shield,
but I will take your dirty life.
Alps!
You will suffer in pain.
You will not be able to escape!
Because of you, my
daughter is fighting to survive!
Is Poena alive?
My Halime is alive!
-Are the wells poisoned?
-Yes, sir.
What you think is victory will be your
disaster. You will die here, Osman!
Release us!
-Leave us!
-Let us go!
-Stop!
Leave us! Leave us!
Leave him, man! He is just a child!
Mother, are you alright?
Mother! Mother! Help us!
-Mother, are you alright?
-Leave my kid!
Leave us alone!
Leave these innocent people alone.
-Mother! Mother!
-You vile dogs.
I'm going to kill you! Attack!
Don't be afraid.
We won't harm you.
All of you will see the justice of Islam.
The cruel times are over.
You will speak your language
and perform your religion freely.
Don't be worrying.
From now on, a new era will begin in Mudurnu.
Hristo! We're drawing back!
Alps, go after her!
That's enough!
They sacrificed you for themselves and left!
Don't you see?
Open your eyes!
Bala Hatun!
Bala Hatun.
There is a cross around his neck.
He's a Byzantine soldier disguising as an alp.
People of Goynuk! This is
the man who shot your sister!
A cross around his neck
and the emperor's seal on it!
Hoo! Hoo!
Speak.
It was the order of Master Sofia and Claudius.
They put ourflag down. Go raise it again.
We avenged you. Do you see now
what kind of game they are playing?
Do you see how they infiltrate?
Don't you see, people?
They turn you against each other.
You're throwing your neighbors, sisters
and brothers into the fire because of them.
We aren't your enemy.
Everybody under Osman
Bey's flag, Turks or Greeks,
...is under our protecting as
long as they follow the rules.
But if you riot, get deceived
and rebel once more time,
...then neither Osman Bey nor I
can keep our swords in their sheathes.
We came here to repair this city not to burn it.
We came here to unite people not to divide them.
These lands belong to all of you.
Pay your tax, show respect and live in peace.
Now drop your weapons.
Then you will repair this city together.
You opened the wounds so you have to cure them.
My Bey, Claudius ran away
through the secret passages.
Let him run. Time is ticking for him.
The booty found in the treasure room, my Bey.
This booty will give everyone strength, my Bey.
-With strength, we will conquer many other lands!
-Yes, my Bey.
Hand out this one for the sword right of Turks.
-As you order, my Bey.
Come on, brothers. Take it.
My Beys and alps.
We won against the heathens, thanks to Allah.
Mudurnu has become a land of Turks.
God willing, we will
prosper this place with Islam.
-God willing, my Bey.
-God willing.
They have set out, my emperor.
And they will be here soon.
Thinking that he got a victory,
Osman will face a greater defeat.
Turks will vanish in Bthynia tomorrow
Halime, my sister.
I will never get angry with you again.
In fact, I never got angry with you.
I got angry with myself...
...that I couldn't recognize you.
I recognized you with my heart...
...and brought you to our tribe.
But I couldn't realize that you were my sister.
I couldn't recognize you.
I couldn't accept that you were the enemy.
But it wasn't your fault.
Despite Sofia's evil plans,
you managed to remain pure.
It was our fault.
We failed to protect you.
We couldn't protect you but
you sacrificed yourself to save us.
Sister.
Did you really forgive me?
Thanks to Allah!
Thanks to Allah.
Thanks to Allah, Halime!
You are alright, aren't you?
Thanks to Allah.
Mother! Mother!
Mother! Halime has waken up!
Thanks to Allah.
Of course! Of course, I forgave you!
My mother always says
there is good in every trouble.
She is right.
Look at her!
My dear.
Halime! Thank Allah, you have waken up!
Thankfully, Allah spared your life for us!
Oh my precious!
Are you alright? Do you have any pain?
No, mother. I'm good.
Very good.
Mother! Mother!
Ulgen, get animals sacrificed
and hand it out to people!
My daughter has waken up!
Thanks to Allah! Other great news!
Thanks to Allah.
What is the other news?
Mother.
White pigeon has brought good news.
Mudurnu belongs to Kayi now.
Oh really? Thanks to Allah.
What a great day!
-Thanks to Allah.
Father has sent us orders to go to
Mudurnu when Halime wakes up.
Oh... Halime can't go anywhere like this.
Well.. I can go, mother.
You still have a wound.
She will go, mother. We'll
go slowly by a carriage.
Fine.
Fine. Start the preparations then.
My Beys, our lands are growing larger.
Yet the number of non-Muslim
people is increasing too.
The question isn't capturing
the land but managing the land.
A new management should be
established in Mudurnu, my Bey.
You're right, Koca Bey.
We'll establish such a management that
it will be the sign of our next conquests.
And everybody will know that Kayis
bring justice and order everywhere.
-God willing, my Bey.
-Hasan Bey.
-My Bey.
You proved yourself with your courage and faith.
Thank you.
You have the command in Mudurnu.
Thank you, my Bey.
Repair the holes in the city walls.
Clean the water in the wells if it's poisoned.
Don't worry, my Bey.
I will carry out the duty
quickly and investigate.
Excuse me now.
Alright.
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too.
Where are you going, Turgut Ghazi?
Well... White-bearded
elders never stop. Alaaddin.
Our conquest has hurt the heathens very
much. They will definitely make a move.
We'll go to the borders and check around.
May you have a safe travel.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, my Bey.
May Allah be pleased with you.
Come on, Solgur Agha. Time to go.
Let's go.
Dying in a bed is forbidden for a Turk.
As long as those elders live,
we will never get defeated.
For sure.
Put it in front of the animals.
Give me.
Take it.
Water is clean, for sure.
If the water were poisoned,
the animals would have noticed.
People! Water is clean, for sure!
You can drink safely.
Come on. Come on, fill your bottles.
Here.
Thank you.
May God protect you.
Come on sisters, come on.
The table is not ready yet.
If my Hatun was here, this
table would be talking by now.
That's how skillful my Hatun is.
Come on, come on sisters,
they will come soon! Please!
Come on! Come on!
So, Alaeddin, tell me.
Where is your mother?
How is Halime? Is she alright?
We sent a pigeon, my Bey. But
we still haven't received news.
Alright. Alright.
Bala.
My Bey.
Why didn't you tell us you were coming?
Huh, my Fatma?
My beautiful duaghter.
My Bey...
-Bala.
Where is Halime?
Hatun, why are you not saying a thing?
Nothing bad happened, right?
Is Halime awake?
Halime... How is Halime?
Where is Halime?
Huh?
You cannot get rid of me that easily!
Halime
Halime.
My daughter!
Halime. My daughter!
Come here.
Come, come.
Are you feeling better?
How are you feeling?
Look at me. Look at me.
How are you? Are you alright?
You are. You are alright.
She is even making jokes.
Praise be she is really strong.
May your victory be blessed my Bey.
Thank you. Thank you.
When I have you with me... I
have my daughter with me here...
There is no greater victory than that.
What happened?
It seems like you want to say something.
I didn't want to ruin your reunion
but there was a rebellion in Goynuk.
We suppressed it. Don't worry.
Who did it?
Did you catch them?
Sofia.
She came to finish what
she started. But she failed.
I wounded her, she escaped.
She won't escape again.
Since you suppressed it, okay then.
No one can ruin our happiness
today. My daughter is here with me too.
Let's go then. Come on, come on, come on.
Hatun.
It doesn't look like your
tables but we will eat anyway.
Can anyone compete with you?
Sure, they cannot cook like I do.
Right.
But it's good, I will handle it.
The table needs your touch.
Father, stop talking. Let's eat.
I have come a long way, I am hungry.
See? See.. Did you hear him?
Your only concern is food, only food.
Who did you get this from?
Really Ghazi, who did you get it from?
Father, you know I got it from you.
True.
You are right.
Ghazi.
I am hungry.
Don't waste time. Come on.
See?
He also turned Yigit to himself.
I feel so thirsty.
Sister, come on, come here.
Give me some water.
Thank you. In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
I am still thirsty. Sister,
come, give me some more.
Alright.
Thank you.
In the name of Allah.
I am still thirsty.
Give me some more.
Thank you.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
You've become really thirsty, my
Hatun. Did you come here running?
Thanks to Allah.
Thank you sister.
Enjoy.
I'll go and check around.
Sure.
Come on.
Go.
Come on!
Come. I'll show you something.
At the last moment, we had to retreat,
my Emperor, but we were very close.
Being very close does not change anything.
Goynuk is still in their hands.
Also, Mudurnu is still in their hands.
And Lord Nikitas died.
Osman is advancing more day by day.
And you cannot stop him!
Osman entered Mudurnu.
But he will not get out of there alive, sir.
All wells have been poisoned.
Osman will check the water before using it.
Sofia is right.
How are you so sure your plan will work?
The poison does not show itself at first, sir.
It takes time. So they will not suspect anything.
Then it spreads through the
body and gives such pain that...
They will not find an
antidote either. Don't worry.
Good.
I liked that you did not stop fighting
even while retreating, Claudius.
Also, it will be very useful for
the big plan I prepared for Osman.
What do you have in mind, sir?
We will surround Osman from all
sides at his most vulnerable moment...
...and strike a blow that
they have never seen before.
How?
Be patient Claudius.
You will learn after dinner.
Draw water from the well.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
In the name of Allah.
Allah.
My Gonca.
My Alaeddin.
Are you alright, my rose?
I am alright.
Are you alright, Alaeddin?
You haven't slept for days.
You seem tired.
I am alright, my rose. Don't worry about me.
We conquered Mudurnu.
My Halime is alright.
All my tiredness disappeared.
Thanks to Allah.
Would you like to drink some water?
Drink some water.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
Here.
Hatun..
I don't want water...
I am really hungry.
What are we going to do?
You are hungry?
Allah Allah, I am really surprised, Alaeddin.
You are surprised, huh?
Your husband asks for food,
and you are mocking with him.
-No way, would I ever do that?
-That's what you are doing.
No, towbah.
Good. Come then.
So you can eat some food, huh?
You sometimes get hungry then, alright.
Sometimes.
Sometimes. You sometimes get hungry.
Stupid Claudius!
He thought he could defeat Osman!
You lost again!
Your defeat will give me
a new tribe and new lands.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
How dare you?!
The water is poisonous!
Claudius have poisoned the wells.
Poisonous, huh?
But Hasan checked all the waters.
They said it was safe.
This poison hides itself until it brings death...
..and kills immediately.
Claudius..
You will take your revenge with this poison, huh?
Attention!
Osman Bey!
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too, my Bey.
You may sit.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
May our victory be blessed.
After Goynuk, Mudurnu has
also become the land of Turks.
We still have a long way to
and many castles to conquer.
Come on now. Don't let the meals get cold.
Eat.
Enjoy.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
Here my daughter.
Here, sister.
Thank you, brother.
Sister...
These meals are not as delicious
as the ones we cooked, right?
Right, sister.
Look... This is not how you should cook the meat.
But you cook meat like a master.
When my Fatma was afraid of
losing her sister, she forgave her.
They made peace.
I knew it, my Bala. I knew this would happen.
My sister, did you say she'd cook it well?
No, she cannot cook.
She just thinks she can cook. Right, my Hatun?
Brother... -No..
It was really good
although it was her first time.
Do you think it is easy to cook, Alaeddin Bey?
Is that so?
-Right.
My daughters cook well.
They do, my Bey. They do.
In this family, I am always
the one who is left out anyway.
Do not make my son upset!
His mother is always behind him!
My dear mother...
Good thing I have my mother
with me... Or you would torture me.
My son.
Mother.
Is he acting like this because
my he was born in a cave?
Fatma.
Is that what you are saying, Fatma Hatun?
You'll need my help one day for sure.
As long as Osman Bey leads the way, none
of those castles can stop us, Hasan Bey.
Right, Yigit brother?
Right, brother. True.
I swear we can conquer all, Koca Bey.
We first conquered Goynuk after
we left the tribe. And now, Mudurnu.
May it last, God willing.
God willing, God willing Hasan Bey.
God willing
Enjoy, uncle.
You seem happy.
Thank you, my nephew.
We took Mudurnu.
We took Goynuk.
Why would I not be happy?
We will conquer many lands together.
In the name of Allah, the merciful,
the compassionate.
Drink some sherbet. Ulgen
prepared this sherbet for Halime.
I asked her to prepare more.
It will take your tiredness away.
My Ulgen...
Are you alright, my Hatun? You seem pale.
I am alright. I am...
What happened brother?
May it be good God willing.
Allah Allah..
Come on brother. Come on..
You'll be alright.
What is happening here?!
No one understood what it was, Hasan
Bey. Everyone is getting sick one by one.
The horses and sheep that
drank water in the morning died too.
The water...
The water is poisoned.
Send the Alps to the wells. Come on!
No one else should drink the water. Go!
As you order, Hasan Bey.
My Allah..
My Allah, help me stay calm.
Help us, my Allah.
I am alright..
My Ulgen, what is happening?
Mother, you sweat a lot.
Here we go.
-Mother.
-What's going on?
-Alaaddin.
-Ulgen.
Cerkutay, my stomach...
-My stomach...
-Ulgen.
Ulgen.
What's going on?
-Mother.
Ulgen, do you hear me?
She said she has a stomachache.
-Ulgen.
She turned all pale and
said she had a stomachache.
My Ulgen? Ulgen?
-Ulgen, do you hear me?
-Ulgen?
Hold on, Ulgen.
Father, something is happening to the alps.
My Shahzade, do something. My Shahzade...
They got poisoned.
-Cerkutay Bey, come on! To the healing house!
-Hold on, my Ulgen. Hold on.
-Come on.
-Cerkutay. She will be alright, brother.
Take the poisoned ones
to the healing house quickly!
Come on, my Shahzade.
I also feel dizzy, brother.
Hasan Bey!
Nobody drink water! Nobody!
My Bey, the water is poisoned.
-The animals that drank water has died.
-Are you saying that just now?
I examined it but the poisoned took effect later.
-I'm sorry.
-Hasan Bey.
Alps!
Clean the wells immediately!
I can't stand anymore, brother.
My Bey, you drank water too.
I'm good. Don't worry.
My emperor.
You still didn't tell us what kind
of game you prepared for Osman.
Be patient, Claudius. You will see soon.
This is the sign of the divine guardians of Rome.
-The greatest army of Rome.
-The Guardians.
Tens of ships carrying blood-thirsty soldiers
are going to reach the land tomorrow morning.
This army won't kill only Osman...
...but also everyone in the frontiers
and actually all the Turks in Anatolia.
I was expecting something big
but I couldn't guess this much.
The Guardians are coming in
trading ships to hide themselves.
You two will welcome them.
Together, we will destroy
whatever belongs to Osman.
I will wipe out the name of Kayi.
There won't be a single tent left.
We will have much fun, huh?
It will be very enjoyable to
destroy Kayi with this army.
But before you go there tomorrow, you
need to find out what happened in Mudurnu.
Your spy will open the gates of
Mudurnu and Goynuk for The Guardians.
Of course, my emperor.
Then we should leave without wasting time.
Excuse me.
My Ulgen... Ulgen, my wife.
My Ulgen? Ulgen?
My Ulgen.
Gulce.
Boil basils and thymes.
Add french lavenders too. It will cure the blood.
Well... Bring alant too.
-It strengthens the lungs. Hurry
up -Of course, my Shahzade.
Come on.
Hatun, make Ulgen drink this.
Alright.
Your cure is here.
-Come on, Ulgen. In the name of Allah!
-Come on, Ulgen. Drink it.
O Healer, O Healer, O Healer
Drink a little more Ulgen. Hold on.
In the name of Allah,
the merciful, the compassionate.
O Healer, O Healer!
Mother.
Don't die, mother.
I promise I will never upset you again.
I swear, mother.
Don't say such things, Ghazi.
Your mother will be alright.
She'll be alright, my boy.
Mother...
Mother.
She has a high fever, Cerkutay Bey.
Did Ulgen drink too much water?
When she came home, she drank half a bottle.
So... Did she drink during the dinner?
-It's affecting Ulgen too fast.
-She did, my Shahzade.
She said she was thirsty and kept drinking.
Did she?
Mother.
-Ghazi.
-Mother.
Don't cry, my dear.
Cerkutay.
Ulgen, my wife.
It's like my body is melting, Cerkutay.
My lungs are burning.
Am I going to die?
-Cerkutay.
-Mother.
Am I going to die?
I won't let that happen. You are strong.
You can fight this, my Ulgen.
She can. My mother can.
Mother? Mother?
-Ulgen?
-Mother?
-Mother!
-Ulgen! Ulgen
Mother!
Don't leave me, mother!
-How can I live without you?
-My Ulgen?
Mother.
-Come here.
-Ulgen.
-Ghazi. Ghazi.
No! My mother...
-Come here.
-Mother, don't leave me.
Come here and pray for your mother.
-Mother.
-Come on, pray for her.
Mother, her fever is too high.
Don't go, my wife.
Don t leave me. Don't
Don't.
My Bey.
What will I do now?
She will be alright. Don't worry.
She will be alright.
Alaaddin, is she alright?
She drank too much water,
mother. It's affecting her too fast.
What about the antidote?
I'm trying to find, mother.
I'm doing my best.
Your father drank water too.
My father?
I trust you.
I won't disappoint you, father.
Innkeeper, bring food to us.
No food left, stranger. As
you see, we are closing.
Obviously, they are preparing for something.
Food here can feed an army.
It seems soldiers are going to eat here.
But why would they want to stay here?
You're right, Turgut Ghazi.
An army is going to eat here.
You? Sofia's cringing servant Hristo.
Let me help you.
This preparation for the emperor's
hidden army coming from Constantinople.
If an army were coming from
Constantinople, I would know.
You can't know, Turgut Ghazi.
Because they are coming in a trading ship.
They intend to kill all the Kayis.
Why would I trust you?
Claudius poisoned the
wells in the castle of Mudurnu.
Everybody drinking water there is dying.
With the army coming, they
will burn down everything.
Believe me, Turgut Ghazi.
There is food here enough
for an army, Turgut Ghazi.
If you are lying to me, I will skin you alive.
Come on, Solgur Agha. Let's go.
Do I have permission, my Bey?
Come in, girl.
Gonca, how is Ulgen doing?
The poison affected her too much, father.
She isn't well.
Hardly breathing.
And she has a weak pulse
Alaaddin thinks she's not doing well.
But he didn't tell Cerkutay Bey.
What about the antidote?
They mixed two different
poisons. He couldn't find it yet.
He can slow it down but too
many people got poisoned.
The old can't survive.
The young still resist.
What kind of demons are they?
They're doing this to their own people.
What kind of demons?
Father, are you alright?
-Father?
-Osman! Osman.
Father, you are sweating
Did you drink water too?
-Osman.
-Father.
-Mother.
-I'm fine. I'm fine.
-Gonca, go let Alaaddin know! Hurry!
-Alright.
My Osman..
Father.
Osman... -My Bey...
Cerkutay.
My Ulgen..
Our son is entrusted to you.
Ulgen... Don't say that...
Protect each other.
Mother, don't say those things!
You are not going to die, right?!
You are not going to die...
You will not leave me alone.
Don't be upset, my dear boy...
Don't be upset.
You will hold on Ulgen. You will hold on!
Alaeddin.
My father got sick!
My Bey.. My Bey...
Don't be afraid..
My Hatun..
You will be alright!
Ulgen..
Ulgen...
My Bala.
My Bala
My companion...
My sister...
Give me your pardon please.
You did so many things for me.
It is all yours, Ulgen.
But don't say that.
Cerkutay.
My Hatun
If you marry another woman, I will haunt you.
Don't get lonely...
Do not starve, my Cerkutay.
Ulgen!
Mother! Mother, don't!
I bear witness...
No! No!
...and I bear witness that Muhammad is....
Ulgen...
...His servant and Messenger.
Mother! Mother, don't!
Mother!
What am I going to do without you?
Do not leave me, mother!
What am I going to do here?!
Why did you leave me alone?!
Don't die mother! Don't die...
What am I going to do now, mother?!
"Indeed we belong to Allah,
and indeed to Him we will return."
Mother... Mother open your eyes!
Mother!
The poison has spread all over Mudurnu.
They are desperately looking for the antidote.
Good.
Let them look for it.
They won't be able to find it.
This poison was made from the
snakes and scorpions of Otranto.
Everyone who believes in Osman will die in pain.
Including Osman.
Don't worry.
Osman is also poisoned.
He has been barely able
to stand since last night.
He will soon fall to his deathbed.
Good.
I feel sad that he'll die
without seeing Rome's guards.
I mean... I am almost going to feel sad.
Rome's guards?
The emperor's most fierce and
undefeated army is coming here.
When they arrive, they will burn
everything that belongs to Osman.
The end of Kayis has come.
Wait for news from me.
When we come to Mudurnu
and Goynuk, I will need you.
Okay.
It all happened because of me!
I hurried.
I acted too quickly.
I wish you had waited a little longer, Hasan Bey.
It wouldn't have happened then.
What is done is done.
I am afraid of what will happen now.
Come on Hasan Bey. Come on.
How would you know the
poison would show itself later?
Come on!
Koca Bey.
What if Alaeddin Bey can't find the antidote?
My Osman Bey...
Osman Bey was also poisoned.
What if something happens to
Osman Bey because of me, Koca Bey...
Hasan!
It all happened because of you!
I didn't know, Cerkutay Bey!
My Hatun died because of you!
I couldn't know...
I did not.. -Shut up!
Shut up!
And he is still defending himself!
People are dying because of you!
Damn you!
Cerkutay Bey!
Do you think I am not suffering in pain, huh?!
Come!
Please, don't!
Stop!
Stop. Stop, Hasan Bey.
What are you doing?!
Pull yourself together!
What happened to you?
It all happened because of this careless man!
Our people and our Osman Bey
have been poisoned because of him!
He has my Hatun's blood
on his hands, Turgut Ghazi!
He will pay for this!
Where is Osman Bey?
I need to see him now.
Osman Bey is in his room, Turgut Ghazi.
Tell me something, my son.
My father is going to be alright.
Right, brother?
The poison spreads.
There is no way to treat this
illness without finding the antidote.
You will all die, one by one.
Look at how majestic they are, Sofia.
The greatest and undefeated
army of the Roman Empire.
They will die by the sword of this wild army.
Osman has also been poisoned.
He can barely stand.
The gates are open.
No one inside is protecting them.
Look... Do you see?
Our fate to destroy Osman is written together.
The sun of Byzantium,
Bitinya will burn the Turks.
Maybe...
Maybe that sun will warm your heart a little too.
You betrayed me.
Even the fire of hell cannot warm my heart.
When we kill Osman, my heart
will warm us both. Don't worry.
To believe this...
...I need to take it out and
see it with my own eyes.
Everyone get ready!
Goynuk and Mudurnu will
become the nightmare of the Turks.
Father...
Ghazi..
Tell me my mother did not die, father.
Tell me my mother is alive.
Tell me it was all a dream, father.
Ghazi..
Your mother became a martyr.
Father.
I am asking you... Is my mother alive?!
Tell me she is alive, father!
Tell me my mother is alive, father!
Tell me my mother is alive!
Ghazi.
Ghazi, come here. Come.
Ghazi, Ghazi.
Ghazi..
My mother is dead, Bala Hatun!
Mothers should never die, Bala Hatun!
They should never die!
They shouldn't.
Mothers never die.
They always live in the hearts of their children.
How can I live without my mother, Bala Hatun?
I know, Ghazi. I know, my dear.
Yet your mother would never
want you to be upset and cry.
How can I endure without my mother, Bala Hatun?
How can I live without my mother?
Time, my boy... Time, my dear.
It cures all the wounds.
A big suffering in your small heart.
But your mother raised
you as such a strong boy...
...that you will endure.
Time will pass and you will grow older.
And you will be a brave alp.
You will have many victories.
Your mother will be happy with your happiness
and wait for you in heaven, my dear.
Seyit, listen to me carefully.
You will take over the
watch from Hasan Bey's alps.
There will be only our alps
on the walls of Mudurnu.
Come on.
Well..
I did my part.
Now it's your turn, Claudius.
We'll enter Mudurnu through
the dense forest in the west.
Osman will never know we are coming, Claudius.
Undefeated soldiers of Great Rome!
You take the smell as we
get closer to Mudurnu, right?
It's the dirty, filthy and
stinking goat smell of Turks!
While Osman is fighting
against the death in his bed,
...we will bury them here where they deserve!
Deep in hell!
Nobody can stop us!
-Nobody can stop us!
-Claudius!
How is that possible?
As long as I live, I will never let that happen.
Osman!
As you didn't die but came to me
yourself, this place will be your grave!
You won't even have a grave.
This is a homeland for the
friendly and a grave for the hostile!
You ruled with blood and will
drown in your own blood now.